<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King. A proclamation for the prorogation of the Parliament, from the sixteenth of Ianuarie next comming, to the three and twentieth of the same moneth</title>
            <title>Proclamations. 1620-12-28</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1620</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A22242</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8650</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S100945</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99836772</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99836772</idno>
            <idno type="VID">1058</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A22242)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 1058)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1572:24)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King. A proclamation for the prorogation of the Parliament, from the sixteenth of Ianuarie next comming, to the three and twentieth of the same moneth</title>
                  <title>Proclamations. 1620-12-28</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
                  <author>James I, King of England, 1566-1625.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>by Iohn Bill, printer to the Kings most excellent Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>M.DC.XX. [1620]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dated at end: Westminster the xxviij. day of December, in the eighteenth yeere of his Highnesse reigne ... .</note>
                  <note>Steele notation: great standing Westminster; Arms 14.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the originals in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery (Early English books) and the British Library (Misc. Brit. tracts).</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament --  Rules and practice --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  James I, 1603-1625 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="royal_proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:1058:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 10 -->
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <p>I R</p>
                  <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>¶ By the King.</head>
            <head type="sub">
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> A Proclamation for the prorogation of the Parliament, from the ſixteent<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of <hi>Ianuarie next comming, to the three and twentieth of the ſame moneth.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas the Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie, for certain<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> great</hi> and vrgent cauſes concerning his Highnes, and the ſtate and <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of his Realme and Church of England, hath ordained a Pa<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ament to be begun &amp; holden at the Citie of Weſtminſter the ſixteent<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> day of Ianuary next comming: For which cauſe diuers Writts ar<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>lready directed foorth for all Prelates, Noblemen, and States of thi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Realme: And alſo for all Knights, Citizens, and Burgeſſe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> choſen or to be choſen for the ſaid Parliament, perſonally to appeare and be preſent at the day and place aforeſaid in ſuch ſort and order, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> like caſes hath beene heretofore vſed and accuſtomed: Yet notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding, his Highneſſe for diuers good cauſes and conſid<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ations him moouing, and with the aduice of his Priuie Councell, hath thought good and neceſſary to prorogue the ſaid Parliament, vntill the three and twentieth day of the ſame moneth o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Ianu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>arie next comming; And therefore his Maieſtie by this his Proclamation, doth pu<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ſh and notifie the ſame to all the ſaid Prelates, Noblemen, and States, and alſo to all <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Knights, Citizens, and Burgeſſes, ſo that they or any of them are not bound or com<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>lled to appeare the ſaid ſixteenth day of Ianuarie at the Citie aforeſaid, but that they and euery of them thereby are diſcharged thereof againſt his Highneſſe: Willing neuertheleſſe, and charg<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ng and commanding all and euery the ſaid Prelates, Noblemen, and States, and all the ſaid <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Citizens, and Burgeſſes and all others to whom in this caſe it ſhall appertaine, that they and euery of them doe perſonally appeare, and be preſent at the ſaid three and twentieth da<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of Ia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuary, at the Citie of Weſtminſter aforeſaid, to Treate, Conſent, and Conclude vpon s;u<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>h mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, which in the ſaid Parliament then and there of the Common Councell of the ſaid <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> (by Gods fauour) ſhall happen to be ordained: And further his Highneſſe chargeth and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandeth all Sheriffes, and other Officers appointed, for, or concerning the choiſe of the <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Knights, Citizens, and Burgeſſes, that they and euery of them doe proceede, touching the choiſe of the ſame Knights, Citizens, and Burgeſſes, in ſuch ſort and order as ought <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o haue beene done, if the ſaid Parliament were not prorogued as aforeſaid: And further to keepe their day of appearance, at the ſaid three and twentieth day of Ianuarie, at the Citie of Weſtminſter aforeſaide, in all points as to them in this caſe appertaineth.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Giuen at his Maieſties Palace of Weſtminſter <date>the xxviij. day of December, in the eighteenth <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>re of his Highneſſe Reigne of England, France and Ireland, and of Scotland the foure and fiftieth <gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                        <desc>••••</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/>
God ſaue the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Imprinted at London by IOHN BILL, Printer to the Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie. M.DC.XX.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
